# Andre Azzolini

## Senior full-stack engineer

apazzolini@gmail.com | https://azzolini.io

I'm a full-stack engineer in Dallas, TX that specializes in modern JavaScript development. I view programming as a craft to be appreciated not only for the end product, but for the code itself. I believe that there's a strong tie between the elegance and simplicity of a codebase and its correctness, performance, and ability to handle change.

# **Experience**

Freelancer Oct. 2014 — Present

- Architected and built a personal CMS to power azzolini.io in ES2016 using React/Redux/Hapi.js/Universal rendering.
- Managed a Scala team in integrating components of a telecommunication company's ordering system to automate several flows.
- · Developed an integration testing framework to facilitate CI for a large, Dockerized microservices-based project.
- · Created a web application from a Material Design specification for interfacing with Cisco telephony equipment.
- · Implemented a real-time admin interface for managing touch-enabled screens used for directory services in commercial buildings.
- Led a development team, architected, and implemented a user-customizable dashboard that integrated with multiple internal applications for a health services company.

#### **Broadleaf Commerce** (Senior Engineer)

Oct. 2011 - Oct. 2014

- Designed and implemented several large, key components of the Broadleaf Commerce codebase, including the migration of the previous
  GWT admin application into its current Spring / Spring MVC / Thymeleaf iteration.
- Drove internal quality and modernization initiatives including moving to git and GitHub from Subversion, standardizing code formatting and styles, and migrating to a versioned documentation system.
- · Oversaw multiple concurrent client implementations and fostered positive, ongoing relationships.
- · Self-prioritized time between client support, client implementations, framework development, and resolving framework issues.

Credera (Consultant) May 2010 — Oct. 2011

- Programmed multiple subsystems of an eCommerce site for a Fortune 1000 company utilizing Java, Spring, and HTML/CSS/JS.
- Performed various production infrastructure tasks such as tuning Apache httpd / Tomcat, handling production deploys, debugging production-only issues, and ensuring maximum site uptime.
- · Trained multiple new team members on general application structure and the various technologies utilized in the project.

## Skills

- Frontend: ES2016 JavaScript (via Babel), React, Redux, Immutable.js, Angular, Mocha, Webpack, CSS3/SASS, HTML5, jQuery
- Backend: Node, Hapi, Express, Java, Spring, Hibernate, Solr, Scala, Akka, Spray, SQL (MySQL, Oracle), Mongo, Firebase
- Devops: Unix, OS X, Jenkins, CI, Docker, Heroku, Tomcat/vFabric, JVM tuning, server config/management, security/cryptography
- · Project Lifecycle: Code architecture, dev team leadership, agile development, project management, code review, git/GitHub/Gitlab
- Languages: English (native speaker), Portuguese (fluent spoken, working knowledge written)

## Education

#### The University of Texas at Austin

December 2010

• Bachelor degrees in Computer Science and Management Information Systems